Illusion sets the stage. Deception reveals the truth.
Experimenter is a drama, history film directed by Michael Almereyda.
Yale University, 1961.
Stanley Milgram designs a psychology experiment that still resonates to this day, in which people think they’re
delivering painful electric shocks to an affable stranger strapped into a chair in another room.
Despite his pleads for mercy, the majority of subjects don’t stop the experiment, administering what
they think is a near-fatal electric shock, simply because they’ve been told to do so.
With Nazi Adolf Eichmann’s trial airing in living rooms across America, Milgram strikes a nerve in popular culture
and the scientific community with his exploration into people’s tendency to comply with authority.
Celebrated in some circles, he is also accused of being a deceptive,
manipulative monster, but his wife Sasha stands by him through it all.
Stanley Milgram, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
Alexandra "Sasha" Milgram, played by Winona Ryder.
James McDonough, played by Jim Gaffigan.
Paul Hollander, played by Edoardo Ballerini.
John Williams, played by John Palladino.
William Shatner, played by Kellan Lutz.
Experimenter: The Stanley Milgram Story also known as the Experimenter, is a 2015 American
biographical drama film written, directed and co-produced by Michael Almereyda.
It depicts the Milgram experiment in 1961 by
social psychologist Stanley Milgram.
The film, co-produced by and starring Danny A.
Abeckaser, also stars Peter Sarsgaard, Winona Ryder, Jim Gaffigan, Kellan Lutz, Dennis
Haysbert, Anthony Edwards, Lori Singer, Josh Hamilton, Anton Yelchin, John Leguizamo.
The film explores themes of experiment, psychology,
controversy, biography, breaking the fourth wall.
The tone is emotional.